Guide to the Communications Workers of America Photographs and Videos PHOTOS.086
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Photographic Prints, 1915-1988; 1960-1988; 4.25 Linear Feet in 3 record cartons, 1 oversize flat box, 2 oversize folders, and 1 flat file folder
  - Subseries IJ: Oversized Photographs.
    - CWA Union-Building School, University of Oklahoma, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Installation Local Leadership, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - International Typographic Union, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - National Federation of Telephone Workers National Assemblies, 1941-1944 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Northwestern Division 2nd Annual Convention, Nov 1950 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Panorama of Fourth Annual Convention, Communications Workers of America-CIO, 1950 (Flat-file-folder 3, Tray 4)
    - Panoramas of International Typographers Convention at Panama-Pacific Exposition, August 1915 and Communications Workers of America Annual Convention, April 1986, 1915, 1986 (Flat-file-folder 2, Tray 2)
    - Panoramas of CWA Security Annual Conventions, 1982-1983, 1986 (Flat-file-folder 8, Tray 3)
    - Portrait of an Unidentified Man from CWA District 9, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Women Telephone Operators at Work in Summer, circa 1935-1949 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Subseries IK: Beatrice Smith Photographs
    - Beatrice Smith Photographs, circa 1940-1969 (Box 3, Folder 18-21)
    - Ephemera, newsletters, certificates, clippings, 1949-1972 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Medals, plaque, 1958, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Hubert H. Humphrey print, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Subseries IL: Addendum
    - 10th, 11th Assembly photographs, Joseph Beirne memorial, 1944, 1945, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Assorted Photographs, circa 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - AT&T Divestiture: Issues for Negotiation, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - AT&T Strike (Richmond, VA), Feb 1990 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Bahr, Morton; Beirne, Joseph, honors, certificates, 1974-1991 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Bahr, Morton, President's Award, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - China trip, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Committee on the Future, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - CWA Clippings, 1933-2003 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - CWA Day proclamation, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - CWA Executive Board, 1980, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - CWA Legislative Conference, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Convention exhibit materials, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Convention exhibit CD-Rs, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - DC Taxi Drivers, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Democratic National Convention, Jul 1992 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Ephemera-postcards, pennant, clippings, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Jerusalem Social and Cultural Center, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Jobs with Justice, circa 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Joseph A. Beirne Memorial Foundation, circa 1993 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - NABET, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Official Photographs, 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Oklahoma States Workers Union, circa 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Organizing AT&T Paradyne, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Pacific Northwest Newspaper Guild Strike, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Picket sign, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - PTTI Inter-American Advisory Committee Meeting (Caracas), circa 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Rally, circa 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Secretary-Treasurer Meetings, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Space Shuttle Columbia flag, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Strike: Picketing G Maflower Hotel in Washington, DC, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Tony Coelho, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Watts, Glenn, correspondence re photo file, 1965-1984 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - West Virginia Newsletters, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - WVSE Newsletter Photos Vol. 4 No. 1, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - White House, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Jimmy Carter letter and photograph, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Photos and clippings from Marie Scheuermann, 1961, 1983, undated (Box 13)
- Series II: Slides, circa 1915-1986; 1970-1985; 6.5 Linear Feet in 5 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, and 1 photograph box
  Series II: Slides contains slides, mostly color, primarly from the 1970s through early 1980s. These slides include images of conventions, union members at work, job training, portraits, and training instructions.
  - CWA Conventions and Assorted Images, circa 1969-1986 (Box 5, Box 6, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9)
    Five linear feet, consisting almost entirely of color slides (estimated total 8,500) stored in 424 slide pages, in five record boxes; a small number are unmounted. Most of the images in the first four boxes were shot at CWA conventions (the conventions of 1969,1973-1978,1979, 1981,1983;1984-1986). The slide pages in the first four boxes are numbered from 28 through 416. The fifth box contains various color slides and a small number of black and white negatives. Subject matter consists of miscellaneous CWA images (including job training, legislative hearings, conventions, and etc.) spanning from the 1970s through the mid-1980s. All but 54 of the slide pages are dated.
  - CWA: Watts + Knecht, circa 1915-1985 (Box 10, Box 11)
    Approximately 675 slides (mostly color) from 9 slide carousels labelled "CWA: Watts + Knecht; 1A; 9 projectors." "CWA: Watts + Knecht; 1B; 9 projectors." "CWA: Watts + Knecht; 1C; 9 projectors." "CWA: Watts + Knecht; 2A; 9 projectors." "CWA: Watts + Knecht; 2B; 9 projectors." "CWA: Watts + Knecht; 2C; 9 projectors." "CWA: Watts + Knecht; 3A; 9 projectors." "CWA: Watts + Knecht; 3B; 9 projectors." "CWA: Watts + Knecht; 3C; 9 projectors." Miscellaneous images ranging from portraits, to "people at work", to planets and stars in space. Dates range considerably from around the early 20th century to mid-1980s.
  - Miscellaneous Slides, circa 1980 (Box 12)
    Approximately 130 color slides from around 1980. They are stored in five slide containers. The images in the first four containers, consist of miscellaneous CWA images (including job training, interviews, repairs, and etc.). The fifth container contains color slides of training/retraining instructions. Also indluced are approximately 228 color 35mm slides from Communication Workers of America conventions of 1974, 1975, and 1977.
- Series III: Horace Rairdon Scrapbook, circa 1940-1975; 1.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 oversize flat box.
  Historical/Biographical Note
  Horace Rairdon was the CWA representative for Fargo, North Dakota from the 1940s through the 1970s.
  Series III: Horace Rairdon Scrapbook contains materials separated from Rairdon's scrapbook and photocopies of the original scrapbook. Materials include photographs, publications, correspondence, and a transcript of a 1970 interview with Rairdon (conducted by a graduate student at the Center for Labor and Management at the University of Iowa).
  - Horace Rairdon Scrapbook, circa 1940-1975 (Box 13)
  - Horace Rairdon Scrapbook: 3 Loose Photographs and 6 Scrapbook Pages, circa 1940-1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Series IV: Videos, 1985-1995; 0.25 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box.
  Series IV: Videos contains five VHS tapes, including "CWA Membership Service, Priority One," "Union Family Action Program," "Donahue/Easterling News Conference," "The 1984 CWA Legislative Conference," and one unlabeled tape.
  - Videos, 1985-1995 (Box 14)
  - "Fasanella", VHS and teachers' activities guide, undated (Box 17, Video 1)
  - CWA workshop, 1982 (Box 17, Video 2-3)
  - CWA interview of Harry Beck, KVAL-TV, "Through the Looking Glass", 1980-11-22 (Box 17, Video 4)
  - CWA TV spots, PSAs, 1977, 1979, undated (Box 17, Reel 1-5)
  - Pauline Bewernick, 1980-04-03 (Box 17, Reel 6-7)
  - Video documentation, 1974-1988 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - America's High-Tech Future (Box 17)